
let questions = [
  {
    question: "What is the full form of RAM ?",
    answer: "Random Access Memory",
    options: [
      "Random Access Memory",
      "Randomely Access Memory",
      "Run Aceapt Memory",
      "None of these"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "What is the full form of CPU?",
    answer: "Central Processing Unit",
    options: [
      "Central Program Unit",
      "Central Processing Unit",
      "Central Preload Unit",
      "None of these"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "What is the full form of E-mail",
    answer: "Electronic Mail",
    options: [
      "Electronic Mail",
      "Electric Mail",
      "Engine Mail",
      "None of these"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "IC chips used in computers are usually made of:",
    answer: "Silicon",
    options: [
      "Lead",
      "Silicon",
      "Chromium",
      "Gold"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "One Gigabyte is approximately equal is:",
    answer: "1000,000,000 bytes",
    options: [
      "1000,000 bytes",
      "1000,000,000 bytes",
      "1000,000,000,000 bytes",
      "None of these"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following is not an input device?",
    answer: "VDU",
    options: [
      "Mouse",
      "Light pen",
      "Keyboard",
      "VDU"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following is used to Manage DataBase?",
    answer: "DBMS",
    options: [
      "Operating System",
      "Compiler",
      "DBMS",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following is an example of non-volatile memory?",
    answer: "ROM",
    options: [
      "None of the above",
      "RAM",
      "ROM",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "File extensions are used in order to ……….",
    answer: "Identify the file type",
    options: [
      "Name the file",
      "Ensure the filename is not lost",
      "Identify the file",
      "Identify the file type"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "bit stands for",
    answer: "binary digit",
    options: [
      "binary information term",
      "binary digit",
      "binary tree",
      "Bivariate Theory"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "1 GB is equal to",
    answer: "230 bytes",
    options: [
      "230 bits",
      "230 bytes",
      "220 bits",
      "220 bytes"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "How many bits are used in the data bus?",
    answer: "16",
    options: [
      "7",
      "8",
      "9",
      "16"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: ".How many buses are connected as part of the 8085 microprocessor?",
    answer: "3",
    options: [
      "2",
      "3",
      "5",
      "8"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: ".……………. is processed by the computer into information.",
    answer: "Data",
    options: [
      "Data",
      "Numbers",
      "Alphabets",
      "Pictures"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "One kilobyte is equal to:",
    answer: "1024 bytes",
    options: [
      "1000 bytes",
      "100 bytes",
      "1024 bytes",
      "1023 bytes"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "In binary code, the number 7 is written as -",
    answer: "111",
    options: [
      "110",
      "111",
      "101",
      "100"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "In which generation of computers, transistors were used?",
    answer: "Second",
    options: [
      "First",
      "Second",
      "Third",
      "Fourth"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "'ALU' stands for?",
    answer: "Arithmetic and Logical Units",
    options: [
      "Arithmetic Long Unit",
      "All Longer Units",
      "Around Logical Units",
      "Arithmetic and Logical Units"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "The term 'Pentium' is related to -",
    answer: "Microprocessor",
    options: [
      "DVD",
      "Hard Disk",
      "Microprocessor",
      "Mouse"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following is the most powerful type of computer?",
    answer: "Super Computer",
    options: [
      "Super-micro",
      "Super Computer",
      "Micro Computer",
      "Mini Computer"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "The most common type of storage devices are ………",
    answer: "magnetic",
    options: [
      "persistent",
      "optical",
      "magnetic ",
      "flash"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "The ………… tells the computer how to use its components.",
    answer: "operating system",
    options: [
      "utility",
      "network",
      "operating system",
      "motherboard"
    ]
  },
  {
    question: "Which one of the following is not a linear data structure?",
    answer: "Binary Tree",
    options: [
      "Array",
      "Binary Tree",
      "Queue",
      "Stack"
    ]
  }
];



